-Flamme. -Call me Master.
-弗蘭梅 -叫我師父
What is it?
什麼事？
Do you really think it's a dirty trick?
師父真的認為這樣的手段很卑鄙嗎？
Frieren, do you remember Basalt's last words?
芙莉蓮，妳還記得 巴扎爾特最後所說的話嗎？
I don't.
不記得
They use words to deceive humans.
他們用語言來欺騙人類
That's right. They are nothing but monsters who can speak.
沒錯，他們只不過是會說話的魔物
That is the reality of those beings that I call demons.
所謂的魔族，本質即是如此
They play dirty tricks.
他們手段卑鄙
And so we have to play even dirtier tricks.
那麼我們就要比他們更卑鄙
If that's what it takes to eliminate the demons,
如果這樣就能殺光魔族
I will gladly accept a bad reputation.
那我樂意為此背負惡名
ORIGINAL STORY BY KANEHITO YAMADA / TSUKASA ABE
（原作：山田鐘人，作畫：阿部司）
I can't stop bleeding.
血止不住了
So this is it, huh?
就到此為止了嗎？
With this, your plan has failed.
這樣你們的計畫就失敗了
I guess so.
是啊
But Frieren won't be left unharmed.
不過芙莉蓮無法全身而退的
She must be fighting Mistress Aura by now.
那傢伙正在和阿烏拉大人戰鬥吧
Last time, we had to retreat because of the party of heroes,
以前是因為有勇者一行人 才不得不撤退
but now there are no heroes to protect Frieren.
但現在保護芙莉蓮的勇者已經不在了
Frieren is no doubt a threat to us.
芙莉蓮對我們而言確實是個威脅
But her level of mana is nothing compared to Mistress Aura.
不過阿烏拉大人的魔力遠在她之上
If she fights her head-on,
正面迎戰的話
Frieren will definitely lose.
芙莉蓮必敗無疑
If that's the case, Mistress Frieren will win.
這樣看來，芙莉蓮大人會贏呢
She's not the type of person who would ever fight a demon head-on.
她不是那種會跟魔族正面交戰的人
She will kill Aura by deceiving her.
阿烏拉一定會上當而被殺死
What nonsense… As far as I can remember,
胡說什麼？我一直記得
Frieren the Slayer has always fought us head-on…
葬送的芙莉蓮都是和我們正面迎戰…
Why do I feel like I'm missing something?
這種違和感是怎麼回事？
This girl's mana is weak…
這個小姑娘的魔力很弱
But I was overpowered by the amount of magic that she fired at great speed.
但我確實受到 她快速釋放的大量魔力所壓制
So how was she able to do that without running out of mana?
為什麼她那麼做卻沒有耗盡魔力呢？
I see!
原來如此！
I can't believe it…
沒想到竟然是這樣
So Frieren is the same as you?
芙莉蓮跟妳一樣吧？
How dirty.
真是卑鄙
You two should be ashamed to even call yourselves mages.
妳們簡直就是魔法使的恥辱
Mistress Frieren knows that all too well.
那種事芙莉蓮大人再清楚不過了
How horrible…
真是悽慘
A village of elves, huh?
是精靈的村莊嗎？
Basalt the Throne,
玉座的巴扎爾特
one of the Demon Generals of the Demon King's army.
是魔王麾下的將軍之一
I'm guessing he led his troops to destroy the village.
就是他率領軍隊摧毀村莊的吧
Are you the one who killed him?
幹掉他的人就是妳嗎？
You half-dying girl.
快死掉的精靈
What immense mana.
好強大的魔力
I bet you're strong.
妳很強吧？
Did you fight the demons head-on?
妳和魔族正面迎戰了嗎？
How ridiculous. That's so stupid.
真是荒謬，有夠愚蠢
Why do people try to fight them head-on?
幹嘛要正面迎戰呢？
You can run, hide, or catch them by surprise.
逃跑、躲藏或是出奇不意的偷襲
There are so many other options.
明明有這麼多選擇
I don't understand what it feels like to be a powerful mage.
真是搞不懂強大的魔法使都在想什麼
You should know.
妳應該能懂的
Huh?
什麼？
You should know how I feel.
妳應該能懂我的想法
Because you are
因為妳
a much more powerful mage than me.
作為魔法使，妳遠比我要強得多了
What made you think so?
妳為何會這麼認為？
It's a hunch.
直覺
What's your name?
妳叫什麼名字？
-What happened to the village? -Completely annihilated.
-村子怎麼樣了？ -沒有活口
The women and children were killed too.
女人跟小孩都被殺光了
I couldn't protect them.
我沒能保護好大家
Even though I was the strongest.
明明我是最強的那一個
You really are stupid.
妳真是個笨蛋
If I were you, I would've run away without even thinking.
如果我是妳，肯定會毫不猶豫地逃走
-Let me down. -I won't.
-放我下來 -才不要
You have talent, so I'm taking you in as my apprentice.
妳很有天賦，我要收妳作弟子
And I'm sure you're aware of it,
我相信妳也很清楚
but if I hadn't passed by, you would've died.
如果不是我剛好經過，妳早就沒命了
On top of failing to protect the village,
不僅沒能保護好村子
you were about to die.
還差一點送命
That's what you call dying in vain.
真的是枉送性命呢
We're being followed.
有人追來了
They're stronger than the general you killed.
比妳剛剛殺掉的將軍還強
Aren't they funny?
他們很有趣吧？
They concealed their mana until the last minute
直到剛剛都還隱匿魔力的氣息
and were obviously trying to ambush us,
想要暗中偷襲
but as soon as they saw that we were mages,
但一發現我們是魔法使
they proudly showed themselves.
就自負地現身了
They play dirty tricks and are cunning,
魔族的手段卑鄙又狡猾
but they all have a ridiculous sense of pride when it comes to magic.
但對於魔法 卻都有一種不可理喻的驕傲
Human mage,
人類的魔法使
leave that elf behind.
放下那個精靈
Will you let me go if I do?
我照做的話就會放過我嗎？
The Demon King's orders were to massacre
殺光所有精靈
all of the elves.
這是魔王的命令
I don't care about your life.
妳的命不重要
Is that right?
是這樣嗎？
Frieren,
芙莉蓮
it's true that I know too well how powerful mages feel.
我確實很清楚 強大的魔法使都是怎麼想的
And I know exactly how these demons feel too.
而且我也很清楚魔族是怎麼想的
They have pride and confidence
對於鑽研至今的魔法
in the magic that they've devoted their lives to studying.
他們極其驕傲自負
In other words, it's worthless arrogance and carelessness.
換句話說，就是垃圾般的傲慢與大意
Frieren, unlike you, these demons
芙莉蓮，我跟妳不一樣
assumed that I was weak.
這些魔族認為我很弱
They were excellent mages of a higher caliber,
這些傢伙雖是優秀的魔法使
but they died because they let their guard down.
卻因為一時大意而送命
You limit the amount of mana that emits from your body to hide your strength?
妳控制了體外魔力的釋放 好讓對方無法判斷強弱？
That's right.
沒錯
I take advantage of their misconception of my mana to deceive and kill them.
我利用他們誤判魔力這點 反過來殺死他們
It's a dirty and despicable method
這種方式既卑鄙又低劣
that makes a mockery of honorable magic.
將神聖的魔法玩弄於股掌之中
Your wounds are looking much better.
妳的傷口看起來好很多了
Shall we start training soon?
差不多該開始修行了吧？
-Flamme. -Call me Master.
-弗蘭梅 -叫我師父
Demons took everything away from me.
魔族奪走了我的一切
Me too.
我也是
I hate them so much I want to eliminate all of them.
我對魔族恨之入骨，我想殺光他們
But I like magic.
但我喜歡魔法
I do too.
我也喜歡
So we don't need anyone else to play dirty tricks that
所以說，玩弄魔法的卑鄙小人
make a mockery of magic.
有我們兩個就夠了
What do I have to do to train?
我要進行什麼修行？
Try to let out less than a tenth of the amount of mana you usually emit.
妳試著將體外魔力的釋放量 控制在平時的十分之一以下
As I expected, you're suppressing it well.
真不愧是妳，控制得很好
Any elf can do this much.
只要是精靈都能做到這種程度
Now keep that up while learning the basics.
接下來就維持這種狀態進行基本訓練
We'll increase your fundamental mana.
藉此提升妳的基本魔力量
-That's all? -It's easy, right?
-這樣就可以了嗎？ -很簡單吧？
By the way, for how long do I have to suppress my mana?
話說我要這樣控制魔力多久？
It's tiring to do it for too long.
維持太久的話會很累
For as long as me.
跟我一樣
Your entire life.
一輩子
You will deceive demons for as long as you live.
妳要用一輩子去欺騙魔族
Lügner died.
琉古納死了
Now all of your executioners are gone.
這樣妳的斬首吏就一個都不剩了
You failed, Aura.
妳失敗了，阿烏拉
Yes, that's too bad.
是啊，真是可惜
But if I can defeat you here,
但如果能在這裡解決妳
that'd be a worthy achievement.
那也算是了不起的成就了
In this battle, you released
在這場戰鬥中，妳從我的控制下
many of my immortal soldiers from my control.
解放了很多不死的士兵呢
Was it really wise to
在我面前
expend that much mana in front of me?
消耗這麼多魔力沒關係嗎？
The Scales of Obedience.
服從的天平
You place both souls on the scale
將雙方靈魂放到天平上
and the being with greater mana subjugates the other.
擁有更多魔力的一方 就能讓另一人服從命令
Aura is able to use this risky spell because of her
阿烏拉之所以可以 使用這種高風險的魔法
tremendous amount of mana.
是因為她自身擁有很強大的魔力
Generally, mana increases
一般來說，魔力會
according to the amount of time you have trained.
隨著修行的時間增長而變多
I can tell from the mana that Aura emits
從阿烏拉釋放出體外的魔力量
that she is a greater demon that has lived over 500 years,
就能看出她是活超過五百年的大魔族
and that she has dedicated most of her life to training.
而且她幾乎這輩子都在修行
500 years, huh?
五百年嗎？
That's a very long time, even for a demon.
就是以魔族而言，也算很長壽了
She must've been invincible up until now.
恐怕到目前為止都沒遇過敵手吧
I can get this much information just from the mana emitting from her body.
光是從她釋放出體外的魔力 就能得到這麼多情報
Despite that, demons don't hide their mana.
儘管如此，魔族不會藏起魔力
They can't hide it.
應該說根本無法藏
How pitiful.
真是可悲
Auserlese.
服從魔法
Master,
師父
demons are cunning, right?
魔族都很狡猾吧？
Why don't they suppress their mana at all times, like you do?
那他們怎麼沒像妳這樣 抑制自己的魔力呢？
They just can't.
因為做不到
Although demons are all about individualism,
雖然魔族的世界講究個人主義
in order to fight humans,
但為了與人類抗爭
they need at least some sort of social structure.
他們需要維持最低程度的組織關係
What do you think is necessary in a society?
妳認為組織的基本是什麼？
-Order? -That's right.
-秩序？ -沒錯
In other words, you need an important person to lead the society.
換句話說，組織會需要領導人物
For humans…
對人類而言…
In this country, for example,
以這個國家為例
status and wealth decide who is important.
地位跟財富決定 一個人是否可以成為領袖
That well-dressed person who came out of the palace is important.
剛剛走出宮殿 身穿華服的人就是領袖
It's hard to tell who is important,
要判斷誰是領袖很難
so people dress up like that in order to make it obvious.
所以人們才會穿成那樣 好讓其他人能一眼就看出來
Demons are different?
魔族不一樣嗎？
They haven't changed ever since they were monsters.
魔族從他們還是魔物時就是如此
Strength equals importance.
強大的人就是領袖
It's much easier to tell than humans.
比起人類，他們更容易判斷
You can see how strong they are.
孰強孰弱，一眼就能看出來
Mana, right?
是魔力吧？
To them, mana means the same thing
對他們而言，魔力就相當於
that status and wealth mean to humans.
人類的地位與財產
You can even say it's their dignity.
甚至可以說是他們的尊嚴
They may temporarily hide
雖然他們有時會為了隱藏行蹤
their mana as a way to go under the radar,
而暫時抑制自己的魔力
but no one is stupid enough to limit their mana on a daily basis.
但是沒人愚蠢到每天都在抑制魔力
There's a big difference between a noble going incognito to visit the castle town
隱藏身分巡訪街市的貴族
and a noble relinquishing their status and wealth, right?
跟放棄自身地位與財富的貴族 是完全不一樣的吧？
And demon society is not kind enough to give those with little mana
而且魔族的社會可沒那麼溫柔 魔力低弱的傢伙
any sense of dignity.
不配擁有尊嚴
That's why the stronger the demon is,
所以越是強大的魔族
the more they flaunt their mana.
越是努力釋放魔力，展現自身的力量
To them, nothing good comes from constantly limiting their mana.
對他們而言，不斷限制自身的魔力 根本沒有半點好處
The thought doesn't even cross their minds.
說到底，他們從沒想過要抑制
It's pitiful, isn't it?
真是可悲，不是嗎？
Just as humans are bound by status and wealth,
就像人類受到地位與財產所束縛
demons are bound by mana.
魔族也受到魔力的束縛
They take pride in magic
明明他們以魔法為榮
and love magic more than anyone,
比任何人都要熱愛魔法
but they don't have freedom over their own mana.
但是卻無法自由運用自己的魔力
Frieren, you're lucky you weren't a demon.
芙莉蓮，好險妳不是魔族
Yeah. Thanks to that, I can deceive demons.
是啊，多虧這點我才能欺騙魔族
It's been three years since you began suppressing your mana, huh?
從妳開始抑制魔力之後 已經有三年了啊？
I knew I could expect a lot from you.
我果然沒看錯妳呢
You look the part now.
有模有樣了呢
Frieren, do you still like magic?
芙莉蓮，妳現在依舊喜歡魔法嗎？
What's this all of a sudden?
為什麼突然問這個，師父？
So-so, I guess.
普普通通吧，我想
In the past,
很久以前
you said you liked magic without hesitation.
妳毫不猶豫地就說妳喜歡呢
That was only 50 years ago.
也才五十年前的事吧
That's true.
說得也是
In the end,
結果
I could only teach you how to fight.
我只有教妳如何戰鬥
Spells to get revenge.
全都是用來復仇的魔法
-Do you regret it? -No.
-妳後悔了？ -沒有
I'm glad that I entrusted my spells to you.
我很慶幸把我的魔法託付給妳
With your long lifespan,
妳的壽命很長
you'll be able to reach a level where you can defeat the Demon King.
遲早能夠達到打敗魔王的地步
Frieren, I have one favor to ask you.
芙莉蓮，有件事我想拜託妳
What is it?
什麼事？
Make the area around my grave a field of flowers.
讓我的墓旁變成一片花田
-That's unlike you. -I know.
-和妳真不搭 -我知道
Frieren,
芙莉蓮
my favorite spell
我最喜歡的魔法
is the spell to create a field of flowers.
就是可以變出花田的魔法
My parents taught that to me when I was small.
那是我小時候，父母教給我的魔法
It's the reason why I started to like magic.
也是我開始喜歡上魔法的契機
Teach me that spell.
把那個魔法教給我吧
Listen, Frieren.
聽好了，芙莉蓮
Don't think about leaving your mark on history.
不要想著名留青史
Live modestly.
要不起眼地活著
You will leave your mark on history when you kill the Demon King.
打敗魔王的那天 妳自然就會名留青史了
I heard there was a mage that has been living in this forest for ages.
聽說這座森林裡 有一個活了很久的魔法使
Is that you?
就是妳嗎？
I've been living for a long time,
我是活了很長一段時間
but I've just been killing time.
但也只是懶洋洋地過生活
It's not like I'm talented.
並沒有多優秀
-What do you think, Heiter? -Yeah.
-海塔，你怎麼看？ -是呢
Her mana level is about a fifth of mine.
她的魔力大概是我的五分之一左右
-It's so-so. -Who is he? How annoying.
-馬馬虎虎的水平吧 -這傢伙誰啊？真讓人不爽
Go home.
回去吧
You don't have any business with a so-so mage, do you?
你們要找的不是 程度馬馬虎虎的魔法使吧？
No, you're stronger than any other mage I've ever met.
不，妳比我之前見過的魔法使都要強
What makes you think so?
你為什麼這麼想？
It's a hunch.
直覺
Auserlese.
服從魔法
You look happy, Aura.
妳看起來很高興呢，阿烏拉
Are you sure of your victory?
妳確信自己贏定了？
You'll see.
等著瞧吧
Frieren the Slayer.
葬送的芙莉蓮
People came to know her for the first time about 80 years ago.
八十年前才第一次為世人所知
She defeated the Demon King with the party of heroes.
跟勇者一行人打敗了魔王
A mysterious elf mage whose age is unknown.
年齡不詳、神秘的精靈魔法使
But I couldn't care less about how long you've been living.
但妳活了多久我根本不在乎
Your mana says it all.
妳的魔力已經說明一切
I can read you like a book.
我能清楚看到妳的資訊
You may be a talented mage,
也許妳確實是很優秀的魔法使
but your mana is nothing special.
但妳的魔力並沒有特別之處
You've trained for maybe a total of 100 years.
大概就是修行了一百年左右的程度
Not just that, it hasn't even changed since 80 years ago.
不僅如此，跟八十年前相比 根本沒有半點長進
Maybe you were training in areas other than mana,
難道是拿這段時間 去鍛鍊魔力以外的技能嗎？
or maybe you were just killing time?
還是只是懶洋洋地過日子呢？
Either way,
不管怎樣
you are nothing compared to me.
妳的魔力根本遠遠不及我
I win.
我贏定了
Now I will chop off your head myself.
我會親自斬下妳的首級
I didn't even have to go out of my way to exhaust her mana.
根本沒必要特地耗費她的魔力
I was a little too cautious.
是我太過小心了
My immortal army suffered quite a bit of damage,
不死軍隊少了不少人呢
so I have to replenish them.
待會得補充一下
What?
怎麼了？
The scale is tipping toward Frieren.
天平正在往芙莉蓮那邊傾斜
You put my soul on the scale, Aura?
妳把我的靈魂放上天平了呢，阿烏拉
Honestly, I would've had a hard time if you kept attacking with your army.
老實說，如果妳一直用大量的 軍隊壓制我，恐怕我就有危險了
I'm glad you have so much confidence in your mana.
幸好妳對自己的魔力很有自信
I can finally defeat you.
我才能打敗妳
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
You should have noticed by now.
妳現在應該注意到了吧
I was suppressing my mana.
我一直在抑制我的魔力
You judged incorrectly, Aura.
妳誤判了，阿烏拉
That can't be true.
那是不可能的
There's no way I would fail to notice that.
我不可能沒看出妳在抑制魔力
Your mana was not
妳的魔力
unstable or wavering, which are characteristics of suppressed mana.
沒有抑制魔力才有的不穩定或波動
I'm surprised.
真令人吃驚
Demons are able to observe mana in such detail, huh?
魔族對魔力的觀察如此精細嗎？
I guess Master's method was right.
看來師父的做法是對的
I have spent most of my life suppressing my mana.
我一生中幾乎都在抑制魔力
Long enough for it to become natural.
不如說這才是我最自然的狀態
Are you stupid?
妳是笨蛋啊？
Why would you do something so pointless?
幹嘛做這種沒意義的事？
Yes, it's stupid.
沒錯，這樣是很蠢
But I can beat you.
但能讓我打敗你們
Don't be ridiculous!
少開玩笑了！
I'm a greater demon who has lived over 500 years.
我可是活了超過五百年的大魔族
Aura, you are standing in front of
阿烏拉，現在站在妳面前的
a mage who has lived more than 1,000 years.
可是活了上千年的魔法使
Frieren,
芙莉蓮
just as demons deceive people with words,
就像魔族用語言欺騙人類一樣
you must deceive demons with your mana.
妳要用魔力去欺騙魔族
Aura, kill yourself.
阿烏拉，自裁吧
This can't be…
怎麼可能…
How can I…?
我竟然…
-Is there someone who commends you? -A journey to heaven, huh?
-有會誇獎妳的人嗎？ -前往天國的旅途嗎？
-You're in great shape. -The Largest Magical City.
-體態很棒呢 -最大的魔法之都
-What is that? -It's Äußerst.
-那是什麼？ -是歐伊沙斯特
It means we're elves.
我們都是精靈啊
"Winter in the Northern Lands."
《北方諸國的嚴冬》
Subtitle translation by: Kiko Morita
字幕翻譯：洪貞韻